SURYA NARAYANAN

Igsurya30@gmail.com | +91-6369724601 | Linkedin | Website | Bengaluru,India

SUMMARY

A Creative Designer having 4+ years of experience in optimizing user experience through research thought process, innovative solutions, Gathering user requirements, Designing graphic elements, Building navigation components. Combine UX thinking with design execution, to produce usable and intuitive user interfaces.

EXPERIENCE

Sr UX/UI Designer May 2021 - Present

eMudhra Technology Limited, Bengaluru, India

- Provide art direction to other designers. Work with development team to execute design into code.
- Driven to discover and bring qualitative and quantitative hypotheses to drive the product metrics.
- Shape and conduct research with users, staff and stakeholders to shape a holistic view of the total user experience.
- Conduct secondary research to set yourself and the team in the right direction .
- Work collaboratively inside a cross functional team, integrating your design expertise inside an agile environment which resulted 20% increase of the development success strategy.
- Taking Ownership of the the entire product for development.

UX/UI Designer Jan 2020 - May 2021

CIOC FMCG Private Limited, Bengaluru, India

- Developing user friendly interfaces and interaction flows of 10+ applications for mobile and web applications.
- Collaborating with team for consistency of the user experience while taking it step by step to the next level.
- Experience in SaaS platforms, B2B, B2C and/or enterprise products.
- Execute various visual design stages from concept to final hand-off development.

UX Designer Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

Haso Technology Private Limited, Madurai, India

- Practiced UX research under a senior UX Designer, designing daily UI design tasks.
- Get in touch with stake holders to understand what is the basic requirements and how to develop a
 product.
- Have strong understanding of User Experience Design and Design Thinking process
- Engage working on Brochures, Logos, illustrations and vector graphics.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Engineering (B.E)

Aug 2015 - May 2019

Electronics and Communication Engineering K.L.N College of Engineering.

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Skills: UX Research, User Interviews, Survey, User centeredDesign process like Define, Empathise, Ideate, User flow, Sketches, Low & High fidelity wireframe, Visual Design, Prototyping, Mockups, Mood-board, Illustrations.

Design Tools: Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, Adobe XD, Blender, After effects, InVision, UXTweek, Affinity Designer

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Operating Systems: Mac, Windows